EMMANUEL UCHENNA

Experienced software developer and technical writer

Contact

Email:

eunithelp@gmail.com

Phone:

(+234) (0) 811-0863-115

Web Profiles:

https://eunit.me https://github.com/eunit99 https://linkedin.com/in/eunit99

Languages

English French

Summary

Experienced software developer specializing in web development with an interest in web application development. Comfortable working with the command line and using Git version control. Possesses working proficiency in ReactJs, VueJS, JavaScript, HTML5 and CSS3.

Skill Highlights

- HTML5 & CSS3
- JavaScript & jQuery
- SASS/SCSS & BEM
- Bootstrap & TailwindCSS
- Knowledge of SEO
- Web Scrapping

- Storybook
- Responsive Web Development
- Git & GitHub
- ReactJS & VueJS
- RESTful API

Experience

Software Developer – 01/2021 to now

BACF Inc., Remote

- Cooperated with designers to create clean interfaces and simple, intuitive interactions and user experiences.
- Worked with product, tech and design teams to manage large, complex web app development projects for corporate clients.
- Created and launched ecommerce & business WordPress,
 SquareSpace, and Shopify websites.

Frontend Developer – 11/2020 to 01/2021 Credipple, Remote

- Delivered 5+ websites per month that met coding standards and cross-browser compatibilities
- Developed websites using client-side languages

Frontend Developer – 02/2020 to 11/2020

LabsAI, Remote

- Built responsive conversational user interfaces for chatbots
- Built Ella bot, hapBot, and also contributed to the development of Bo – an onboarding chatbot.
- Coding from PSD files into working pages, and themes

Education

Bachelor of Science: Anatomy - 2021

Alex Ekwueme Federal University, Ndufu Alaike-Ikwo, Ebonyi State

Certifications

- Web Design, Web Development JavaScript, HTML5, Git, CSS, jQuery, React.js (certificate): Sololearn, IBM, Cutshort, Coursera, Gymnasium.
- Google IT Support Professional Certificate, PowerBi, EFSET English Certificate (C2 Proficient) (certificate): Google, Coursera, EF Standard English Test (EF SET)
- Business Analysis, Business Model Canvas, Entreprise Design Thinking (certificate): **Open University, Simplilearn.**